<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Thoughts on markets</title>
    <link>https://zyw229.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Thoughts on markets</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 15:59:56 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://zyw229.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Regional banks, how you doin&#39;?</title>
      <link>https://zyw229.github.io/posts/macro003/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 15:59:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zyw229.github.io/posts/macro003/</guid>
      <description>Summary Since 2022, regional banks have been having a hard time. The introduction of the Bank Term Funding Program (BTFP) has tied banking sector stress tighter with overall market liquidity. In this article, we revisit several key metrics we&amp;rsquo;ve been watching since SVB failure to gauge the current stress level within the banking system. Through analyzing past weeks&amp;rsquo; data, we try to project a path forward for regional banks, as well as market liquidity, for the coming months.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Liquidity party is (almost) over</title>
      <link>https://zyw229.github.io/posts/macro002/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 00:01:19 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zyw229.github.io/posts/macro002/</guid>
      <description>Summary The risk asset bull run since start of 2023 has been driven by a series of favorable technical factors. However, with those factors diminishing, it must find new sources of fuel. We argue that a prolonged regional bank crisis might be necessary to sustain this bull run, while a US banking system stablization could, ironically, be the last nail in the coffin for risk assets.
Liquidity run Since start of 2023, market has been gererally upbeat despite weak fundamentals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mini-QE, US version</title>
      <link>https://zyw229.github.io/posts/macro001/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 15:59:47 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zyw229.github.io/posts/macro001/</guid>
      <description>Summary In this article, we discuss the effect of the proposed bank rescue package and why it was risk-positive for the market, and why the debate on whether this is QE is pointless. We argue that the market should only care about the fact that this rescue package achieves similar results of a QE program, at least in the short term.
One thing that caught the market&amp;rsquo;s attention last week was the sudden spike in the Fed&amp;rsquo;s balance sheet, effectively reversing the amount achieved by QT since last November.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
