<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>https://zyw229.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 15:59:56 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://zyw229.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>77 days into SVB collapse, how are regional banks doing?</title>
      <link>https://zyw229.github.io/posts/macro003/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 15:59:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zyw229.github.io/posts/macro003/</guid>
      <description>Summary In this article, we explore the various ways that bank stress mechanically influences overall market liquidity, and revisit the metrics we&amp;rsquo;ve been watching since the SVB failure. Through analyzing past few weeks data, we project that the liquidity situation does not look too promising for the next few weeks. Until next wave of regional banks failures, overall market liquidity will remain tight.
Bank stress 77 days have passed since the SVB and Signature Bank failures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Liquidity party is (almost) over</title>
      <link>https://zyw229.github.io/posts/macro002/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 00:01:19 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zyw229.github.io/posts/macro002/</guid>
      <description>Summary The risk asset bull run since start of 2023 has been driven by a series of favorable technical factors. However, with those factors diminishing, it must find new sources of fuel. We argue that a prolonged regional bank crisis might be necessary to sustain this bull run, while a US banking system stablization could, ironically, be the last nail in the coffin for risk assets.
Liquidity run Since start of 2023, market has been gererally upbeat despite weak fundamentals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mini-QE, US version</title>
      <link>https://zyw229.github.io/posts/macro001/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 15:59:47 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zyw229.github.io/posts/macro001/</guid>
      <description>Summary In this article, we discuss the effect of the proposed bank rescue package and why it was risk-positive for the market, and why the debate on whether this is QE is pointless. We argue that the market should only care about the fact that this rescue package achieves similar results of a QE program, at least in the short term.
One thing that caught the market&amp;rsquo;s attention last week was the sudden spike in the Fed&amp;rsquo;s balance sheet, effectively reversing the amount achieved by QT since last November.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
